<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on conorcroasdell</title>
    <link>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on conorcroasdell</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© Yuanyuan GE 2020</copyright><atom:link href="https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> E-Bike Research 2</title>
      <link>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-11-27-e-bike-research-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-11-27-e-bike-research-2/</guid>
      <description>Research Stage 2, 26/11/18 - 3/11/18:
Parts:
For my first prototype (P1), I chose to use the most simple equipment I could find to mock-up the power system for my motor. For this test, I just wanted to produce a mock-up that would allow me to adjust the speed of the motor with a throttle of some kind, using batteries which are similar in voltage to those I plan to use in my final version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title> E-Bike Research 3</title>
      <link>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-12-05-e-bike-research-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-12-05-e-bike-research-3/</guid>
      <description>Research Stage 3, 3/12/18 - 10/12/18:
To move from the desk test setup to the first ridable prototype, P1. I will need to buy a clamp for mounting to the seatpost or the bikes frame (these seem to be the most straightforward mounting locations so I will focus on them for the first mock-up). I think it makes sense to buy a commercial seat clamp (known as an &amp;ldquo;O-clamp&amp;rdquo; or an &amp;ldquo;axle clamp&amp;rdquo;) as they are readily available and made to fit the range of tube sizes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Bike Research 1</title>
      <link>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-11-25-e-bike-research-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-11-25-e-bike-research-1/</guid>
      <description>Research Stage 1, 19/11/18 - 26/11/18:
I began by researching the different types of e-bikes and the history of e-bikes overall. After settling on the friction drive as the variant which best fits my project, I looked into the existing friction drive offerings, both D.I.Y. and commercial. I found friction drive designs from the late 1800s until now. I particularly noticed the recent trend in popularity of small friction drive kits being released, often through crowdfunding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MUV Air Quality Sensor</title>
      <link>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2019-02-14-muv-air-quality-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2019-02-14-muv-air-quality-sensor/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: I was asked to make a case for the air quality sensor kit for the MUV urban mobility project. An open source citizen science project funded by the EU. To allow it to be easily reproduced by others, the case should use an existing waterproof electronics enclosure and readily available parts. Instructions and the needed files were all published to the MUV GitHub page here: The timeframe from receiving the case to delivering the finished prototype and its documentation was 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MUV Proximity Sensor</title>
      <link>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-12-20-muv-proximity-sensor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-12-20-muv-proximity-sensor/</guid>
      <description>Making a case for the MUV proximity sensor: Proximity sensor, PCB + Components Dimensions:
Screw holes: 51.5mm x 38.75mm
H: 70mm
W: 59mm x 59mm
Proximity Sensor Case, Key points for design:
-Allow NFC to function
-Design for manufacture with Fablab machines
-Ease of assembly
-Access to all buttons and USB port
-Access to battery
-B,C and Tag LEDs all visible
Research and Preparation:
I chose 4mm poplar triplex as a material for the proximity sensor as I think it well suited to the intended application of the proximity sensor; they will be indoors and there will be many of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open E-Bike Kit: Intro</title>
      <link>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-11-24-open-e-bike-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://conorcroasdell.github.io/post/2018-11-24-open-e-bike-kit/</guid>
      <description>An Open E-Bike Kit &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;- Motivation and the Idea:
As part of my internship here at the Fablab I will work on a project of my own. For this I chose to make an add-on E-bike kit which following the open design concept. I came to this idea after moving to the Netherlands and using a bike as daily transport for the first time. The cheapness and effectiveness of the bicycle are clear as is it’s lesser environmental impact vs the car or public transport.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
